<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Nathan&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://nathanielwheeler.com</link>
    <description>A blog about code and whatever I feel like.</description>
    <managingEditor>nathan@mailftp.com (Nathaniel Wheeler)</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 13:32:28 -0600</pubDate>
    <item>
      <title>Blogtober Day 1: Developing an App</title>
      <link>https://nathanielwheeler.com/blog/2020/blogtober-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Blogtober is a month-long challenge to publish a blog post every day for the month of October.  When I realized this event was coming up, I knew that I had to commit for my fresh new blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, for every day of October, I will be writing about the development of my latest project: implementing the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thethemesystem.com/&#34;&gt;Theme System&lt;/a&gt; as a web application.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What is the Theme System?  Instead of setting a yearly resolution into stone and giving up because you missed that one day, you can instead pick out a &#39;theme&#39; for the year (or a season) that guides your endeavors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For example, both of the creators have used the theme &#39;Year of Less&#39;, which translated to a year of less travel and fewer commitments for one, and no new projects for the other.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;collapse multi-collapse show&#34; id=&#34;explanationButton&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;button class=&#34;btn btn-outline-primary btn-block&#34; type=&#34;button&#34; data-toggle=&#34;collapse&#34; data-target=&#34;.multi-collapse&#34; aria-expanded=&#34;false&#34; aria-controls=&#34;explanationButton themeSystemExplained&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#x9;Click here for a more lengthy explanation.&#xA;&lt;/button&gt;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;collapse multi-collapse&#34; id=&#34;themeSystemExplained&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe class=&#34;embed-responsive-item&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/NVGuFdX5guE&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;text-center&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Co-creator CGP Grey explains the Theme System &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;.multi-collapse&#34; data-toggle=&#34;collapse&#34; aria-expanded=&#34;false&#34; aria-controls=&#34;explanationButton themeSystemExplained&#34;&gt;(hide)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Implementing this system as a web application is something I have pondered ever since I heard of it last year.  I&#39;ve been putting it off either because I believed I didn&#39;t have the skills or because life was too crazy to start a new project.  But now, I&#39;m at a spot in life where I believe I can reasonably get this done.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow, I&#39;ll start prototyping the website.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Inktober: Day 1&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not only is it Blogtober, it is Inktober, where you make an ink drawing for every day of October!  I&#39;ve started with something simple: the &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.golang.org/gopher&#34;&gt;Go gopher!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;card-img-top&#34; src=&#34;/images/posts/inktober20-01.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;The Go gopher on a beanbag chair typing on a keyboard whilst sweating profusely.&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not a good ink wash, but it leaves room to improve.  Tomorrow, I&#39;m going to track down my technical pens and do some &lt;em&gt;crosshatching!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 20:28:22 -0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s Next?</title>
      <link>https://nathanielwheeler.com/blog/2020/whats-next</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now that I have a blog in production, I&#39;ve been asking myself what I should focus on for my next project.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While I am eager to get started on something new, I still have a lot of features I want to add to this blog before I focus my coding elsewhere.  Here&#39;s what&#39;s at the top of my list, in no particular order:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A comment system for blog posts&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Email verification for new accounts, as well as password resets.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sign in with google or some other account verifier&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An RSS Feed&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m still considering what to do after I&#39;ve finished polishing this website.  I&#39;d like to experiment with javascript frontends for a go backend.  I&#39;d also like to make journaling app inspired by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thethemesystem.com/&#34;&gt;Theme System&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 13:28:19 -0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Blog!</title>
      <link>https://nathanielwheeler.com/blog/2020/newblog</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello the internet!  Welcome to the blog of me, Nathaniel Wheeler.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What is this blog for?  I&#39;m glad you asked.  This is a blog for &lt;em&gt;whatever happens to hold my interest at the time of writing.&lt;/em&gt;  This could, potentially, be many things, but let&#39;s not initialize our chickens before they&#39;re defined, am I right?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now, this blog was &lt;em&gt;supposed&lt;/em&gt; to be live way back in February.  Back in December of &#39;19, I had just recently spent three months in an intense code camp learning C# and Javascript web frameworks.  I thought that I could learn another new language by myself in a similar length of time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, February came and went with no website to show for it.  And since March, I&#39;ve moved towns, gone back to school, and learned what a pandemic is.  It might just be me, but I feel like this year has been a bit crazy!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Probably just me though.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 12:54:37 -0600</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>